<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section id="methodology" xml:base="methodology.xml" break="before"
  inexecsummary="yes">
  <title>Methodology</title>
  <section id="planning">
    <title>Planning</title>
    <p>Our general approach during penetration tests is as follows:</p>
    <ol>
      <li>
        <b>Reconnaissance</b>
        <br/>
        We attempt to gather as much information as possible about the target.
        Reconnaissance can take two forms: active and passive. A passive attack
        is always the best starting point as this would normally defeat
        intrusion detection systems and other forms of protection
        afforded to the app or network. This usually involves trying to discover
        publicly available information by visiting websites, 
        newsgroups, etc. An active form would be more intrusive, could possibly show up
        in audit logs and might take the form of a social engineering type of
        attack.
      </li>
      <li>
        <b>Enumeration</b>
        <br/>
        We use various fingerprinting tools to determine what hosts are visible
        on the target network and, more importantly, try to ascertain what
        services and operating systems they are running. Visible services are
        researched further to tailor subsequent tests to match.
      </li>
      <li>
        <b>Scanning</b>
        <br/>
        Vulnerability scanners are used to scan all discovered hosts for known
        vulnerabilities or weaknesses. The results are analyzed to determine if
        there are any vulnerabilities that could be exploited to gain access or
        enhance privileges to target hosts.
      </li>
      <li>
        <b>Obtaining Access</b>
        <br/>
        We use the results of the scans to assist in attempting to obtain access
        to target systems and services, or to escalate privileges where access
        has been obtained (either legitimately though provided credentials, or
        via vulnerabilities). This may be done surreptitiously (for example to
        try to evade intrusion detection systems or rate limits) or by more
        aggressive brute-force methods. This step also consist of manually testing the
        application against the latest (2017) list of OWASP Top 10 risks. The discovered 
        vulnerabilities from scanning and manual testing are moreover used to further elevate
        access on the application. 
      </li>
    </ol>
  </section>
  <section id="riskClassification">
    <title>Risk Classification</title>
    <p>Throughout the report, vulnerabilities or risks are labeled and
      categorized according to the Penetration Testing Execution Standard
      (PTES). For more information, see:
      <a href="http://www.pentest-standard.org/index.php/Reporting">
        http://www.pentest-standard.org/index.php/Reporting
      </a>
    </p>
    <p>These categories are:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>
        <b>Extreme</b>
        <br/>Extreme risk of security controls being compromised with the
        possibility of catastrophic financial/reputational losses occurring as a
        result.
      </li>
      <li>
        <b>High</b>
        <br/>High risk of security controls being compromised with the potential
        for significant financial/reputational losses occurring as a result.
      </li>
      <li>
        <b>Elevated</b>
        <br/>Elevated risk of security controls being compromised with the
        potential for material financial/reputational losses occurring as a
        result.
      </li>
      <li>
        <b>Moderate</b>
        <br/>Moderate risk of security controls being compromised with the
        potential for limited financial/reputational losses occurring as a
        result.
      </li>
      <li>
        <b>Low</b>
        <br/>Low risk of security controls being compromised with measurable
        negative impacts as a result.
      </li>
    </ul>
  </section>
</section>
