<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section>
        <title>About <company_long/></title>
	<p><company_long/> is the world's first not-for-profit computer security consultancy. 
	We operate under an innovative new business model whereby we use a Dutch fiscal 
	entity, called a “Fiscaal Fondswervende Instelling” (Fiscal Fund raising Institution), 
	as a commercial front-end to send 90% of our profits, tax-free, to a not-for-profit 
	foundation, Stichting NL net. The NLnet Foundation has supported open-source, 
	digital rights, and Internet research for almost 20 years.</p>

	<p>In contrast to other organizations, our profits do not benefit shareholders, 
	investors, or founders. Our profits benefit society. As an  
	organization without a profit-motive, we recruit top-name, ethical security 
	experts and find like-minded customers that want to use their IT security 
	budget as a "vote" to support socially responsible entrepreneurship. The rapid 
	pace of our current growth reflects the positive response the market has to our 
	idealistic philosophy and innovative business model.</p>

 <p><company_long/> has a number of values that we describe as our 
 “Core Principles.” These are:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><b>No sketchy stuff</b><br/> 
      We don't build surveillance systems, hack activists, sell exploits to 
      intelligence agencies, or anything of the sort. If a job is even remotely 
      morally questionable, we simply won't do it.</li>
      <li><b>Open-Source</b><br/>
      Releasing ALL tools and frameworks, we build as open-source on our website.</li>
      <li><b>Teach to fish</b><br/>
      During engagements, we will not only share our results with your company, 
      but also provide a step-by-step description of how to perform the same 
      audit or procedure without us. We want to demystify what we're doing. 
      It's not rocket science, and we genuinely want to help your company 
      improve its security posture, even if it costs us repeat business.</li>
      <li><b>IoCs for free</b><br/>Releasing ALL collected threat intelligence 
      (Indicators of Compromise) into an open-source database that everyone can freely use. 
      (Sanitized in agreement with customers.)</li>
      <li><b>Zero days</b><br/>
      We don't sell zero-days - we responsibly disclose them!</li>
          </ul> 
<p>For more information about <company_long/>, we refer you to our website: 
<a href="http://www.radicallyopensecurity.com">www.radicallyopensecurity.com</a>.</p>
</section>
