<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section>
        <title>Team and Reporting</title>

        <section>
                <title>Team</title>
                <p><company_short/> may perform the activities with its core-team 
                members, external freelancers, and/or volunteers.</p>
                <p>First point of contact for this assignment shall be:</p>
                <ul>
                        <li><company_poc1/> (<company_short/>)</li>
                        <li><client_poc1/> (<client_short/>)</li>
                </ul>
                <!-- remove this for non pentesting offers-->
                <p>Our penetration tests are run a bit like a Capture The Flag 
                (CTF) competition:
                <!-- remove this for non pentesting offers-->
                
				<company_long/> has a geographically distributed team 
				and we use online infrastructure (RocketChat, GitLabs, etc.)  
				to coordinate our work. This enables us to invite the 
				customer to send several technical people from their
				organization to join our <company_svc_short/> team on a volunteer basis.  
				Naturally, we extend this invitation to <client_short/> as well.</p>
				
                <p>Throughout the course of the audit, we intend to actively 
                brainstorm with <client_short/> about both the <company_svc_short/> and the process. 
                This is a continuous learning experience for both us and you. 
                Also, in our experience, a tight feedback loop with the customer 
                greatly improves both the quality and focus of the engagement.</p>

        </section>
        <section>
                <title>Reporting</title>
                <p><company_short/> will report to <client_short/> on the <company_svc_short/>. 
                This report will include the steps it has taken during the 
                test and the vulnerabilities it has found. It will include 
                recommendations but not comprehensive solutions on how to address 
                these vulnerabilities.</p>
                
                <p>A sample Pentest report can be found here</p>
					<ul>
						<li><a href="https://github.com/radicallyopensecurity/templates/blob/master/sample-report/REP_SittingDuck-pentestreport-v10.pdf">https://github.com/radicallyopensecurity/templates/blob/master/sample-report/REP_SittingDuck-pentestreport-v10.pdf</a></li>
					</ul>
					
				<p>One of <company_short/>'s Core Principles is the Teach 
				To Fish principle – otherwise known as the 'Peek over our 
				Shoulder' (PooS) principle. We strive to structure our 
				services so they can also serve as a teaching or training 
				opportunity for our customers.</p>
        </section>
</section>
