<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<waivers>
    <standard_waiver>
        <title><company_svc_short/> - WAIVER</title>

        <p><b><i><signee_long/></i> (<i><signee_short/></i>)</b>, with its registered office at <signee_street/>,
            <signee_city/>, <signee_country/> and duly represented by <b><signee_waiver_rep/></b></p>

        <p>
            <b>WHEREAS:</b>
        </p>

<p>A. <client_short/> wants some of its systems to be tested,
                            <company_long/> (“<company_short/>”) has offered to perform
                        such testing for <client_short/> and
                            <client_short/> has accepted this offer.
                        The assignment will be performed by <company_short/>' core-team members, external
                        freelancers, and/or volunteers (the “Consultants”).</p>
                    <p>B. Some of the activities performed by
                            <company_short/> and the
                        Consultants during the course of this assignment could be considered
                        illegal, unless <signee_short/> has given permission for
                        these activities. <company_short/>
                        and the Consultant will only perform such activities if they have received
                        the required permission.</p>
                    <p>C. <signee_short/> is
                        willing to give such permission to <company_short/>, the Consultants and any
                        other person <company_short/> might
                        employ or engage for the assignment.</p>
                    <p>
                        <b>DECLARES AS FOLLOWS:</b>
                    </p>
                    <p>1. <signee_short/> is
                        aware that <company_short/> will
                        perform <company_svc_long/> of the
                        following systems of <signee_short/>, as described
                        below. The services are intended to gain insight in the security of these
                        systems. To do so, <company_short/>
                        will access these systems, attempt to find vulnerabilities and gain further
                        access and elevated privileges by exploiting any vulnerabilities found.
                            <company_short/> will test the
                        following targets (the “<b>Targets</b>”):</p>
                    <generate_targets/>
                    <p>2. <signee_short/>
                        hereby grants <company_short/> and
                        the Consultants on a date to be confirmed by email the broadest permission
                        possible to perform the assignment, including the permission to:</p>
                    <p>a. enter and use the Targets;</p>
                    <p>b. circumvent, breach, remove and turn off
                        any security measures protecting the Targets;</p>
                    <p>c. copy, intercept, record, amend, delete,
                        render unusable or inaccessible any data stored on, processed by or
                        transferred via the Targets; and</p>
                    <p>d. hinder the access or use of the
                        Targets,</p>
                    <p>but <signee_short/>
                        only grants the permission for these activities to the extent that (i) such
                        activities are necessary to perform the assignment and (ii) such activities
                        do not disrupt the normal business operations of <signee_short/>.</p>
                    <p>3. The permission under Article 1 extends
                        to all systems on which the Targets run, or which <company_short/> or the Consultant might
                        encounter while performing the assignment, regardless of whether these
                        systems are owned by third parties.</p>
                    <p>4. <signee_short/>
                        warrants that it has the legal authority to give the permission set out
                        under Articles 1 and 2. It also warrants it has obtained the necessary
                        permissions from any third parties referred to under Article 3.</p>
                    <p>5. Should the public prosecutor initiate an
                        investigation or criminal proceedings against <company_short/> or any of the consultants it
                        engaged or employed as a result of the performance of the assignment for the
                        customer, then <signee_short/> will co-operate fully
                        with <company_short/> in defending
                        against this investigation or proceedings, including by providing any
                        evidence it has which relates to this investigation or these
                        proceedings.</p>

        <generate_waiver_signature_box/>

    </standard_waiver>
</waivers>
